<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tecnicanimal</title>
    <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tecnicanimal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tecnicanimal.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Alpine Ibex</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/</guid>
      <description>Historically present in Central Europe rocky regions, starting from the 16th century through the 19th century, due to overexploitation and poaching, the alpine ibex (Capra ibex) became extirpated in most areas. Remaining populations were only present in the western Italian Alps around the Gran Paradiso and Vanoise massifs.
After the Gran Paradiso was made into a national park in 1922, resulting in ibexes being protected from poaching, their populations grew in surrounding areas, repopulating Italian and French alpine ranges, southern Germany, Switzerland and Austria, mainly thanks to reintroductions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xbox Series X Spatial Audio Setup</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/xbox-series-x-spatial-audio-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/xbox-series-x-spatial-audio-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Importance of audio A good gaming experience is not all about graphics and frame rate. Although they play a big role in making a videogame immersive, in my experience audio is one of the major components that drives sensations when experiencing digital content. The same goes for movies according to George Lucas.
 While stereo sound is one-dimensional, since it’s coming from the front, left and right, surround sound added a second dimension with sound coming from the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Alessandro Bolis and I created this site in order to experiment writing articles and share some of my thoughts about tech, videogames and science.
This is a static site made with Hugo, hosted on Github and deployed through Netlify. The theme i am using is a modified version of this one.
If you wish to contact me for any reason, feel free to go ahead and fill the contact form below or text me via telegram.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/privacy/</guid>
      <description>By visiting this site, you consent to the data practices listed below.
Data collection is at its lowest possible 👀 This site does not collect data about you unless it is voluntarily provided. Examples of this type of data collection is any info submitted in the contact form. This data is not sold to any third parties and is only used for personal uses such as knowing who sent me a contact form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
