<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tecnicanimal</title>
        <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Tecnicanimal</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tecnicanimal.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Alpine Ibex</title>
        <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/main.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Alpine Ibex" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically present in Central Europe rocky regions, starting from the 16th century through the 19th century, due to overexploitation and poaching, the alpine ibex (&lt;em&gt;Capra ibex&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/016815919190262V&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;became extirpated in most areas&lt;/a&gt;. Remaining populations left in the western Italian Alps around the Gran Paradiso and Vanoise massifs. After the Gran Paradiso was made into a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.pngp.it/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;national park&lt;/a&gt; in 1922, resulting in ibexes being protected from poaching, their populations grew in surrounding areas, repopulating Italian and French alpine ranges, southern Germany, Switzerland and Austria, mainly thanks to reintroductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the alpine ibex is not threatened, being considered of Least Concern by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.iucn.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IUCN&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpine ibexes are strictly herbivorous and need to integrate mineral salts into their diet, for this reason are often observed licking stones while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/80269/see-how-alpine-ibex-defies-gravity-all-lick-salt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;risking their lives&lt;/a&gt;, or approaching mountain huts since salt is often scattered by their visitors. As shown here below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;flex-grow: 188; flex-basis: 453px&#34;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_licking.jpeg&#34; data-size=&#34;3000x1588&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_licking.jpeg&#34;
				srcset=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_licking_hu24034a021f3efb1bdd155d54f272fae5_459413_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_licking_hu24034a021f3efb1bdd155d54f272fae5_459413_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
				width=&#34;3000&#34;
				height=&#34;1588&#34;
				loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why I got the chance to observe them from close distance when I visited the &lt;em&gt;Baita Lago Nero&lt;/em&gt; in Valgoglio in the province of Bergamo, a mountain hut located at around 2000 meters above sea level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/img/map.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This altitude corresponds to the snow line in the spring, where ibexes tend to live in this season. A period when males and females are usually not found together, as ibexes tend to segregate sexually and spatially depending on the different seasons. From December to February, during the mating season, females and males live in mixed-sex groups and by May, adults tend to separate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following photographs capture a small group of males wandering near the aforementioned mountain hut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;flex-grow: 66; flex-basis: 160px&#34;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_in_fog.jpeg&#34; data-size=&#34;2000x3000&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_in_fog.jpeg&#34;
				srcset=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_in_fog_hu688f12785f20769b308b815e38d249c5_80853_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_in_fog_hu688f12785f20769b308b815e38d249c5_80853_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
				width=&#34;2000&#34;
				height=&#34;3000&#34;
				loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;figure style=&#34;flex-grow: 150; flex-basis: 360px&#34;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex.jpeg&#34; data-size=&#34;3000x2000&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex.jpeg&#34;
				srcset=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_hu35c0595dfb359f54d0b8baeac2a42a3c_554897_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_hu35c0595dfb359f54d0b8baeac2a42a3c_554897_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
				width=&#34;3000&#34;
				height=&#34;2000&#34;
				loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style=&#34;flex-grow: 150; flex-basis: 360px&#34;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_scratching.jpeg&#34; data-size=&#34;3000x2000&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_scratching.jpeg&#34;
				srcset=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_scratching_hue6f3ef5880be9912cc6fbb5a346c791e_385786_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_scratching_hue6f3ef5880be9912cc6fbb5a346c791e_385786_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
				width=&#34;3000&#34;
				height=&#34;2000&#34;
				loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;figure style=&#34;flex-grow: 66; flex-basis: 160px&#34;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_couple.jpeg&#34; data-size=&#34;2000x3000&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_couple.jpeg&#34;
				srcset=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_couple_hu271c2c87ee3f277bfcac2be3fed58ce6_1179098_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://tecnicanimal.me/p/the-alpine-ibex/alpine_ibex_couple_hu271c2c87ee3f277bfcac2be3fed58ce6_1179098_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
				width=&#34;2000&#34;
				height=&#34;3000&#34;
				loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Xbox Series X Spatial Audio Setup</title>
        <link>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/xbox-series-x-spatial-audio-setup/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://tecnicanimal.me/p/xbox-series-x-spatial-audio-setup/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://tecnicanimal.me/p/xbox-series-x-spatial-audio-setup/Schermata%202021-04-30%20alle%2011.53.03.png" alt="Featured image of post Xbox Series X Spatial Audio Setup" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-importance-of-audio&#34;&gt;Introduction: Importance of audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good gaming experience is not all about graphics and frame rate. Although they play a big role in making a videogame immersive, in my experience audio is one of the major components that drives sensations when experiencing digital content. The same goes for movies according to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://variety.com/2018/film/awards/sound-movie-blade-runner-get-out-phantom-thread-1202705398/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;George Lucas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While stereo sound is one-dimensional, since it’s coming from the front, left and right, surround sound added a second dimension with sound coming from the back. Since we live in a three-dimensional reality, with stereo and surround we are still missing the possibility to hear the thrum of a helicopter flying over our heads or the snow crunch when &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y9B_kXHQi68&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;walking on Europa in Destiny 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Here is where different spatial audio technologies come into play, mainly Dolby Atmos, DTS:X and the inevitable online wars between the fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the main way we listen to game audio effects and music is in stereo. This is because most tv speakers are stereo and manufacturers tend to cheap out on speakers set up even for their flagship models and even those that on paper support surround sound natively, lack real channel separation, failing to deliver a different experience than standard stereo speakers.
What this means is that the proper way to experience multi-channel content is through a dedicated multi-channel speakers’ setup. Even a 5.1 home theater configuration hooked up to an audio receiver could deliver miles better sound experience than the muffling tv speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the main way we listen to game audio effects and music is in stereo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you, like me, don’t own a 7.1 home theater setup in the living room, but still wanted to experience spatial audio? Well maybe there is a way, sort of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;guide-a-pair-of-headphones-is-all-you-need&#34;&gt;Guide: A pair of headphones is all you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how to get the best audio experience from your Series X|S if all you have is a good pair of headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, connect your headset directly to the console and disable any post processing the headset might have on default. Whether the connection is via USB, headphone jack or wirelessly it does not matter for the purpose of the guide since you’ll get spatial audio anyway. In case you do not connect your headset directly to the console, but to the tv or to a HDMI receiver, don’t worry there’s a setting we want to enable later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then go into your &lt;strong&gt;console settings&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;volume and audio output&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/img/foto.png&#34; alt=&#34;foto1&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here on the right side if it is the first time you connect your headset the default audio setting will be stereo uncompressed. Of course, we want to change that to step up the audio game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/img/foto2.png&#34; alt=&#34;foto2&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll be presented with three different options for enabling virtual spatial audio: &lt;strong&gt;Windows Sonic for Headphones&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Dolby Atmos for Headphones&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;DTS Headphones:X&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/img/foto3.png&#34; alt=&#34;foto3&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend trying out Windows Sonic first, since it is the free alternative. From there, if you feel like it, you can take advantage of the free trial period of the other two options which are available only after having downloaded the Dolby Access or DTS Sound Unbound app respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, for those of you connecting your headphones to the tv or to a HDMI receiver, you’ll simply need to tick the checkbox Using an HDMI headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tecnicanimal.me/img/foto4.png&#34; alt=&#34;foto4&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;considerations-and-further-tips&#34;&gt;Considerations and further tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People on online forums seem to suggest that Windows Sonic for Headphones works well for all types of content, while Dolby Atmos for headphones works best for movies (you can even use it for movies that support Dolby Atmos on Netflix).
A note on &lt;strong&gt;in-game audio settings&lt;/strong&gt;, from my experience, and from official settings recommended by Dolby, the best results are obtained selecting the generic “Headphones” audio preset. This way you basically avoid stacking two virtual surround effects on game audio tracks, which would result in distortion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a technical explanation of how these technologies can achieve a virtual spatial sound effect using stereo headphones I suggest to take a look at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.waves.com/3d-audio-on-headphones-how-does-it-work&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;this interesting article&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all, thank you for making it through 🎮.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
